<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Deep thinking</title><link>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/</link><description>Recent content on Deep thinking</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 22:14:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Android OpenGLES learning-draw a color</title><link>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/learning%20opengles%20on%20the%20android-fill%20the%20window.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 22:14:38 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/learning%20opengles%20on%20the%20android-fill%20the%20window.html</guid><description>We know that the screen displays content by emitting RGB lamp beads one by one, and the brightness of the lamp beads is determined by a memory area. By writing data to this memory area, we can observe the data display effect on the screen. This is a complex and flexible job.</description></item><item><title>Modern C++ study guide-template</title><link>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/Modern%20C++%20study%20guide-template.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 21:33:38 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/Modern%20C++%20study%20guide-template.html</guid><description>Template have always had a pivotal role as an important feature of C++, and are a great tool for writing highly abstract code.
What is template #Template are real-life examples: fix the parts that are all the same, leave the parts that change empty, and combine the two parts to form something valid when you use it.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/about.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 23:35:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/about.html</guid><description>Profile #Love programming, love being alone
Technology Stacks # Android Kotlin C++ Python JavaScript HTML/CSS Contact me #QQ:632518410
E-Mail:honguilee@163.com
[Buy me a coffee](https://www.buymeacoffee.com/bravebuffalo)</description></item><item><title>Modern C++ Study Guide - Standard Library</title><link>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/Modern%20C++%20Study%20Guide%20-%20Standard%20Library.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 22:15:05 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/Modern%20C++%20Study%20Guide%20-%20Standard%20Library.html</guid><description>In [the previous chapter](https://www.yuque.com/docs/share/adb5b1e4-f3c6-46fd-ba4b-4dabce9b4f2a?# Modern C++ Study Guide - The Type System) we explored the type system of C++ and proposed a low-to-high and again high-to-low study idea. This article is a study guide from high to low, and hopefully provides a new perspective.
What is standard library #Programming languages are generally divided into two parts, one is the syntax part, such as the type system in the previous chapter, and the other part is the predefined toolset accomplished with this syntax, such as the subject of this article - the standard library.</description></item><item><title>Modern C++ Study Guide - Type Systems</title><link>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/modern-c++-study-guide-type-system.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 11:11:59 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/modern-c++-study-guide-type-system.html</guid><description>In the previous post, we provided a directional guide, but what and how to learn was not developed in detail. This article will build on the previous article and focus on how to learn C++&amp;rsquo;s type system.
Before the start #Before we get into the type system, there is one thing we should agree on - use the modern syntax of C++ whenever possible.</description></item><item><title>Modern C++ Study Guide-roadmap</title><link>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/Modern%20C++%20Study%20Guide-roadmap.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 08:51:01 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/Modern%20C++%20Study%20Guide-roadmap.html</guid><description>C++ is a forty-year-old language that has gone through four major version upgrades (Birth, 98, 11, 17(20), 14 counts as a minor upgrade). Each upgrade was a trade-off between many problems and solutions. Understanding this history can better help us to clarify the development of the language. So next I will borrow its development history, talk about my understanding of it, and finally give a guide to what I think is a more reasonable learning route.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Android NDK-basic concepts</title><link>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/Introduction%20to%20Android%20NDK-basic%20concepts.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 11:30:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/Introduction%20to%20Android%20NDK-basic%20concepts.html</guid><description>Sometimes it is necessary to use libraries written in C/C++ for security, performance, and code sharing considerations during the development. Although with the support of modern tool chains, the difficulty of this work has been greatly reduced, after all, everything is difficult at the beginning, and beginners often still encounter many unpredictable problems.</description></item><item><title>Linux batch file manipulation - based on find,xargs</title><link>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/Linux%20batch%20file%20manipulation%20-%20based%20on%20find,xargs.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 21:19:39 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/Linux%20batch%20file%20manipulation%20-%20based%20on%20find,xargs.html</guid><description>Preface #In the beginning stages of a project, it is common to encounter various file operations, copying header files, libraries, batch renaming, and so on. Once the file structure is complex, this will be a boring job.
Find the files #find searches for files in the directory structure, which is how it is described inside man.</description></item><item><title>horizontal scrolling tabs with plain HTML, JS, CSS</title><link>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/horizontal%20scrolling%20tabs%20with%20plain%20HTML,%20JS,%20CSS.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 09:23:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/horizontal%20scrolling%20tabs%20with%20plain%20HTML,%20JS,%20CSS.html</guid><description>Preface #Not long ago, in one of my projects, I need to show a horizontal scrolling tab, which supports horizontal mouse drag and click to switch. In the process of realization, I found that this small feature needs to use the front-end of the three carriages at the same time, but the realization of the difficulty is not high, and the final result is not bad, is a rare beginner project, so the idea of writing this article was born, I hope that beginners can help.</description></item><item><title>A introduction to Android JNI</title><link>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/Android-JNI-development-introduction.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 21:34:45 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/Android-JNI-development-introduction.html</guid><description>What is JNI #The full name of JNI is Java Native Interface, and as the name suggests, it&amp;rsquo;s a programming method that solves the problem of Java and C/C++ calling each other. It really only solves two aspects of the problem, how to find and how to access. Figure out these two topics and we have learned JNI development.</description></item><item><title>Personal understanding and useage of CMake</title><link>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/Personal%20understanding%20and%20useage%20of%20CMake.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 19:21:49 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/Personal%20understanding%20and%20useage%20of%20CMake.html</guid><description>Preface #CMake is a build tool, through which you can easily create cross-platform projects. It is usually used to build a project in two steps: generating a project file from the source code, and building the target product (which may be a dynamic library, a static library, or an executable program) from the project file.</description></item><item><title>A introduction to Kotlin cotoutine-from zero to multiple</title><link>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/A%20introduction%20to%20Kotlin%20cotoutine-from%20zero%20to%20multiple.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 19:10:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/A%20introduction%20to%20Kotlin%20cotoutine-from%20zero%20to%20multiple.html</guid><description>In the last post, I introduced the creation, use, and collaboration of Kotlin coroutines. This post will introduce more usage scenarios and continue to take you into the world of coroutines.
使用协程处理异步数据流 #Common programming languages have built-in representations of datasets of different objects of the same type, often called container classes.</description></item><item><title>A introduction to Kotlin coroutine-from theory to practice</title><link>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/A%20introduction%20to%20Kotlin%20coroutine-from%20theory%20to%20practice.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 19:02:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/A%20introduction%20to%20Kotlin%20coroutine-from%20theory%20to%20practice.html</guid><description>The previous article partially explained Kotlin coroutines from a theoretical point of view, and this article will continue the journey of coroutines from a practical point of view, based on the previous article.
From the source #In Kotlin, in order to use a coroutine, it first needs to be created using a co-creator, but there&amp;rsquo;s another prerequisite - a co-program scope (CoroutineScope).</description></item><item><title>A introduction to Kotlin coroutine-those unclear relationships</title><link>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/A%20introduction%20to%20Kotlin%20coroutine-those%20unclear%20relationships.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 18:50:29 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://bravebuffalo.cc/en/post/A%20introduction%20to%20Kotlin%20coroutine-those%20unclear%20relationships.html</guid><description>Kotlin&amp;rsquo;s coroutines have been increasingly sought after by Android developers since its introduction. On the other hand, due to its huge API, it has also shut out a considerable number of developers. This article tries to start from a few important concepts of coroutines, in the complex API to restore its original face, to bring readers into the Kotlin coroutine world with a new perspective.</description></item></channel></rss>